Today we are discussing the best health
plans that are available under Rs 15,000
Aditya Birla Active & Max vs
ICICI LB's Elevate Plan vs Care
Health Insurance's Ultimate Care Plan.
Mahavir Chopra The Founder & Chief
Executive [Music] Officer of Beshq.org.
[Music]
Now here's what we'll be covering in
this video.  Number one, a comparison of the
unique features with the fineB.  Two, a quick roll
call of all the core benefits and waiting
periods and the fine.  Third, a detailed look
at the real-world service experience,
starting with customer service and, most
importantly, claims experience.  After a
quick comparison of pricing and finally,
you will understand how these plans are
rated by IM Research.  India's only
independent insurance research platform
that through deep research gives one single data
back rating for all insurance plans.
Making it is to compare all products in
the market.  Starting with the USP.  The
first USP is the wellness program.  Now
this video will be very clear that we are
focusing on insuring that in the long run
you have premiums that are affordable.  So all
the things that we have covered in this are
focused on insuring that you have a good
cover at the same time it is affordable.   The
first USP is the Health Management
Program USP.  What does this do?  This
basically gives you a wellness program by which you can
reduce your premiums by
basically following a specific routine that the
insurance company has defined for you.  So,
every insurance company now days is
basically giving you an app where they give you
certain kind of goals, which if you achieve,
you can get certain discounts.  Well,
let's look at what each of these companies are
offering.  ICI Lum offers up to 30%
discount on your renewal premium, if you
follow the help goals that are defined by
them.  What are these help goals?  Typically
walk at least 4000 steps a day
Participate in webinars, quizzes and
contests related to healthcare Complete
fitness challenges on the app Health
assessments If you do all this, your
premium can be reduced by up to 30% depending
on the points that you get Now Aditya Birla
Activ Max is one of the first plans that came
into the market which started
introducing these wellness programs.
Its wellness program is very
interesting.  You can get up to 100% of your
renewal premium as cashback.
So you will not have to pay any premium.
It also has beans.  You have
goals of some steps.  You can basically go
to the gym and have certain sessions that you do which are
minimum 30 minutes.  Burn a more
than 300 calories.  All these things are
covered by variables and technology.  It happens
through their apps.  That gives you this
discount.  Up To 100% Is What It Is
Offered.  This is the highest that any company is
offering today.  Ah the wellness benefit.  Add on
available in Care Health.  This is not
available.  Otherwise, if you only take the add-on, then it is
offered by Care Health
Insurance and
Ultimate Care.  Here also
your premium can be reduced by 30%.
Similarly, if you follow the steps.
So all the insurance companies are basically
telling you to become healthy.  We will
give you discount.  And that is a win-win
situation.  The advantage for insurance companies is
that you will make fewer claims if you are healthy.
And the obvious benefit to you is that you will also be
healthy.  Plus you will have to pay less premium.
Next we will understand what
bonuses are.  Now, if you are buying a plan keeping a budget in mind, then there are
more chances that your sum insured will typically be less.  So the
bonus plays a very important role for you.
So let's understand how
bonus is covered in all these three banks.   It is
important to understand that the
bonus available in all these three plans is a guaranteed bonus.
There is basically no linkage to
claims.  You will get this bonus anytime
you claim it, not at the time
of renewal.  You just have to renew it.
Let's understand how each of these plans
are offering the bonus part of the feature.  Now
ICICI LBR gives you 20% bonus every year
up to 100% accumulation as a regular feature
and if you take an add on which is
called Power Booster add on then you
get a guaranteed bonus of 100% every year and
this accumulates without any limit so it
means if you have taken an amount of 10 lakhs then
it will become 10 lakhs, 20 lakhs, 20 lakhs, 30 lakhs
and this will keep happening there is no cap on the
accumulation part your accumulation will be
unlimited now moving on to how
Aditya Birla is doing it Aditya Birla calls it
the Super Credit right in this also there is a guaranteed
bonus of 100% every year but the accumulation will be
limited to 500% or 3 crores whichever is less.  Right?  So in this
your sum insured can go up to five times or Rs 3
crore.  Now Care Health also
offers such kind
of a benefit but it is
available as a rider.  How is it being done?
Let's understand.  First let us understand the simple one,
how to get it if you do not take the rider.
So basically the regular is 50%
every year up to 100%.  If you
take this Infinity Bonus add-on,
you get a guaranteed bonus of 100% every year.  And
again the accumulation is unlimited.  So, if
you are thinking of taking plans within your budget, then
these plans which have
unlimited accumulation can be
very beneficial because it
helps you create your sum insured at the
same time reduce premiums and control.
Now next is also equally important
for someone buying an limited budget plan.
Right?  It basically there is a feature that has
recently come up with most plans now.
It's called the Unlimited Sum for One or Two
Claims.  What happens in this is that if you have
taken a sum assured but you think in the back of your mind
that a claim can come at any time
in your lifetime where the claim can go above that thing
and it can be very very
significant how do you pay for that claim this
is the answer to that question basically two
companies ICICI Elevate and Care Health
Ultimate Care offer and add on by which
you can claim one claim in your entire lifetime for
unlimited sum insured there will be
no limitation on your sum
insured you can claim typically there is
an important condition in this which is
specifically mentioned in ICICI lmb that
you can opt for this add on only in the first two years.
Cannot opt ​​out after that.  In case of care, health
is an important condition that you need to
understand.  I just read it out here.  The add-
on can be opted in only at policy
inception.  Meaning, you cannot do it even in the first two years.
You can do this only when you are taking the policy for the first time.
You must
continue paying the premium while renewing this
benefit for five continuous years.  This means that
you will
pay the rider premium for this benefit continuously for 5 years.
आप कभी भी निकल नहीं सकते अगर
आपने यह लिया है, तभी आपको इसका बेनिफिट
मिलेगा।  Otherwise you will not get its benefit.  Now
another premium payback benefit
that is available only in Care Health
Ultimate Care is what I am going to
discuss is again it is an add on you have to
pay a premium.  The interesting
thing is that once in every block of five
claim free years if you do not make a claim for 5 years.  If
you do not make a claim in a block of five years, the
base premium for the first year will be
returned to you.  You will get money back.
Very very interesting for someone who is
basically looking at typically controlling
their premiums.  Right?  This
is a very interesting feature for him.  Otherwise, we regularly do not recommend these kinds
of money back things
in any insurance product.  But here because we are
purely looking at it also
from someone looking at controlling the
premiums it becomes very interesting.
There is one more rider in Care Health
Ultimate Care that becomes very
interesting.  Typically, people who are
youngsters are also basically looking at
a gym membership, which is very, very
unlike how our health insurance regularly
operates.  CareHealth Ultimate Care offers
a rider called the Be Fit Plus
rider that gives you unlimited access to
fitness centres across the country.
We also checked this as we belong to
Vikhroli Powai Mumbai area.
We checked whether good gyms were available
or not.  So when our team checked,
they found out that good gyms were available which they could also go to.
Right?   The
approximate premium was
around Rs 1600 for someone who is 27-28 years old.
So by paying ₹1600 basically per year
you get unlimited access to the gym.
So it becomes interesting.  That's why we
covered it.  Typically, we did not cover this in Most of the
Videos.  But because we are talking about
young people, we are talking about
people who want to get value.  This becomes very very
interesting.  Now
moving on to the core benefit, let us understand the benefits of the one that pays your
hospital bill.  The
room rent
limit is the most important factor that results
in the largest deductions.
They understand what is available.  So in ICSI Lamb,
single private AC room
is available by default.  Which is the cheapest room in the
hospital.
You are eligible for a private room.  If you
want a room above that, then when you are buying the policy,
you can opt for the Any Room option
and due to that you will again get Any Room.
This is an important benefit that
you should understand.  Because if you are
not able to get a room within your eligibility limit
and you take a room above that limit, then
you get a huge deduction in proportionate deduction.
That's why whenever
possible, take any room.  Here
we did a calculation.  Around ₹600
came for a 30 year old family who is
trying to cover himself with his wife and
his kid.  So there was an extra premium of ₹600,
so it makes sense to explore
it anytime.  There is no room limit in Aditya Birla Act Activ Max
and Care Health Ultimate Care.
You do not have any type of condition regarding the room.  All types of
rooms are available.  Now Moving On To Day Care
Treatment, Modern Treatment And Organ
Donor.  All these things are covered
without any boundaries, without any limits.   There is no
list at the day care.  All day
care treatments are covered.  And there are
no limitations on the coverage.  So you are
getting complete coverage.  Which is a very very
good thing.  Now moving on to temporary
exclusion.  This means that when you buy a plan,
not everything is covered from day one.  The
insurance company will keep increasing and improving your cover gradually as
you stay invested.
Right?  The first
limitation in any health insurance plan
is the 30-day waiting period for sickness and
disease-related claims.  When you
buy the policy, you cannot make sickness and disease claims in the first 30 days.
You
can only make accident claims in the first 30 days.  From then on
you can make sickness claims.
That is an ancient thing.  This is the waiting period in both the three plans that we are
talking about.
Next is the specified
disease waiting period.  Specified disease
means a list of diseases.  For those
diseases, the insurance company
imposes a waiting period of two years.  This is also as per
standard IIDA norms.
And there is a list of diseases in it
which as per what I have seen till date are typically
slip disc, kidney stone,
cataract, piles, there are
many such diseases which are
not covered in the first two years.  You get cover from the third year.
This 24 months is applicable in all these three plans.  In
case of ICI Lum Elevate, there is one more
waiting period that is not applicable,
otherwise in most of the standard
plants, it calls for the 90 days waiting
period for couple of chronic diseases.  So
what are these diseases?  This is BP,
diabetes and cardiac conditions.  So, in the
30 days waiting period that I told you about, there is
a 90 days waiting period.
When you buy the policy for the first time,
you cannot claim for BP, diabetes and cardiac conditions.  So instead of 30 days it will
take 90 days.  All the other conditions that I
mentioned are the same.  Only this ICI
Lamb has increased 30 days to 90 days.  For these
three things that that that that that that that that that
mentioned.  BP, diabetes and cardia
conditions.  Please understand this well before we move forward.
Now let's go back to specified diseases.  Let us
understand what modifications are available in it.   There
is only one modification available in specified diseases which is ICS term that you can reduce the term of
24 months or two years to 12 months
by paying additional premium.
So that is how you can basically modify the
two year waiting period.  Now moving on to
the pre-existing disease waiting period.
What kind of waiting period is this?  In this,
whatever existing disease you have, when you
buy the plan, the
insurance company says on those diseases that
I will not cover you from the first day.  I
will cover you after a certain period of time.
Now the standard waiting period is three
years.  There is a waiting period of 36 months.   The
standard waiting period for all three companies is 36 months.
Customizations are available.  That's what I'm
going to explain now.  The first
customization is reducing the waiting
period which is available with ICICI Lumb &
Care healthcare plans.  Basically, you can
reduce the waiting period to 12 or 24
months by paying extra premium.  This is also
available Care Health.  Now there is one more
waiting period modification in the pre-
existing plan that is available in all these
three plans and that is what I am
going to explain to you.  Now what is this
modification?  There are some specific diseases.
Its waiting period can basically reduce
from three years that we already
spoke about to zero to 30 days.  So let me
tell you how this cover is done.
In case of ICICI Elevate, there are basically six diseases for
which you can apply and your
waiting period is if you had
existing diseases while buying the policy.
You can reduce it from 3 years to
just 30 days for these six
listed issues.  What are these illnesses?
Asthma, Blood Pressure, Cholesterol,
Diabetes, Obesity and Angioplasty with
a gap of one year.  तो अगर यह कोई भी डिजीज
है, आप प्लान खरीद रहे हैं, आप एक्स्ट्रा
प्रीमियम पे करके आपका थ्री ईयर वेटिंग
पीरियड को ये वाली डिजीज के लिए 30 डेज
में कन्वर्ट कर सकते हैं।  You will get cover from 31 days.
Aditya Birla Active One
Max also offers this but offers it for
seven listed in this.  So
apart from the six diseases that I mentioned, there is one more
disease called COPD.  Chronic obstructive
pulmonary disease.  Right?  This is also something that can get
this waiting period
reduction.  Waiting period reduction is not 30
days.  In this case the waiting period reduction
is zero days.  This means that you will
start getting cover from the very first day.  These are the seven listed
ailments within Aitya Birla Activ Max.
Now Care Health Ultimate Care also
offers basically the same thing.  Let us
understand how he gives it.  So basically your health care will be
reduced by 30 days.
30 days will be reduced from three years.  The intake will be
for listed illnesses.  In this,
instead of the COPD that I mentioned,
hypothyroidism can be covered.  This is
also called underactive thyroid.  That can be
covered from day 31 in this policy.  So
asthma, blood pressure, cholesterol,
diabetes, obesity, angioplasty and
hypothyroidism can be covered in 31 Day
Care, Health, Ultimate Care.  So
this was basically the waiting period that we have
discussed.  Now we move on to
how is the customer service of these three insurance
companies.  First let us see the response on
toll free.  ResponseOn is toll free.  Slow in
case of ICICI, Quick in case of Aditya
Birla and Quick in case of Kerala.  So,
if you try to talk on toll free number, then
according to our research of ILM, if we try to understand then
you will face some problem with such number.
Rest, there
are less chances of problems in Aditya Birla and Care Health.  Now
how is the response time on X and Twitter as it used to be?  Meaning,
we are trying to give you an understanding of
what is the approach of an insurance company towards
customer service?  So in this case
all these three companies have average performance.
Meaning none of them are good and bad, they are
equally good and equally bad to each of them.
So this is not such a big red flag or green flag.
We can move forward.  Now
Comparing Claims Experience.  Very
important part of the video where we will
understand the claims.
are the charant parameters.  We will
understand which insurance company is doing
well in all the parameters.  The first parameter is basically the
speed of claim settlement.  In this ratio, it is
basically understood that no matter how many
claims an insurance company receives.
How many claims does he settle in the first 30 days?
Try to understand this.
This shows
how fast and efficient the insurance company is in settling
claims.  99.94% in case of ICICI which is
a very very good number.  99.90% in case of
Aditya Birla which is also a very good
number and 100% in case of Care Head.  Meaning, all the
three companies are
behaving like the school toppers, meaning there is basically a difference of two-three
points in the bips.  All
three are very efficient when it goes to
speed of claim settlement and efficiency
claim settlement.  Which is a great thing.
Understand claim complaint.
How many complaints come on claims?
He tries to understand how many people are unsatisfied with the claims.
0.14% in case of ICICI, 16%
in case of Aditya Birla Care Health and
0.47% which is very-very high
almost three times what ICICI and
Aditya Birla basically have as ratios.  So this is
a worrying number.  Meaning, a
lot of complaints are coming in regarding care.  This means that
deductions are being made or claims are being rejected by the
insurance company
and the customers are not satisfied.  That is why a
lot of complaints are coming and are being
registered.  So this is an important
ratio.  This is a small red flag
for Care Health.  Unresolved Claim Ratio
Unresolved Claim Ratio is also a majority ratio.
This ratio tells us that if an
insurance company collects ₹100, then
how much of that ₹100
goes towards claims.  So if the
ratio of an insurance company is between 60 and 80,
then according to our
threshold and the threshold of IM Research,
it is a good
ratio. Right, let us understand
which companies are coming between 60 to 80 and which
companies are not coming.  Right ICICI Lbar
Elevate ICI LBA Elevate
is not the rating of the insurance company.  The increment ratio of the insurance company
ICICI LBR is
85.53%.
Meaning it is above 80 which basically means
that their premium may increase in future.
Because this insurance company will
not be able to sustain these premiums.
₹85 if going to claims out of ₹100.
Commission also has to be paid later.  The
insurance company also has to bear the expenses.
Profit also has to be earned.   If
all these things are not achieved in the remaining 15 years, then the
chances of premium increasing are very high.
75.97% in case of Aditya Bindra
which is falling in the 60 to 80.  So it is a
green flag 66.28% in case of care
which is also falling in the 60 to 80 so
it is a green flag.  Let us understand the claim rejection
ratio.  The claim rejection ratio
is very high.  This is what we have to understand that
how many claims an insurance company rejects, will it
reject my claim or not.
What are the chances of the claim
being rejected?  They understand.  14.11% in case of
ICICI Almarg one on the highest I have seen
on all the videos I have done.  One of the
highest.  Obviously 14% claims are getting rejected.  This
means that out of 100 claims coming in,
ICICI is rejecting 14 claims.  Not a
good ratio.  It's a red flag.  3.98% in
case of Aditya Birla which basically means
that four out of 100 claims are getting rejected.
3.1% in case of Kerala good ratios in
case of Aditya Birla Kerala and not good for
ICIL Now moving on to the most one of the most
important parts of this video premium
because we made this video to
discuss which plans would be good if the premium comes below Rs 15,000.
So let's understand what is the
premium of each of these three plans.  Again,
we have calculated this premium for Mr. Kumar who is our standard persona.
I am 30 years old and am buying this
plan for myself, my wife who is also
30 years old and one child who is one
year old living in Mumbai. Let us understand what will be the premium for Rs 10 lakh sum
insured.
So ICICI
lombard is coming for 13964, Aditya Bla Activ
Max is coming for 14890 just
in the range of 15000 and Care Health
Ultimate Care which is ₹175.  So all these
policies are giving you
health insurance coverage of up to Rs 10 lakh within ₹1000/- per month.
Plus,
if you see, you are getting so many benefits
which I have already told you.  If you make small
additions, you will
get bonus on every claim and your sum insured will increase.  There is
also a feature of your restoration.
Due to this the sum insured may increase.  There are
many others I mentioned that can
reduce premiums.  If you
add and subtract all that, it becomes a very
affordable and comprehensive health
insurance plan for you.  Now before we
end the video one of the most critical
parts of the video is understanding the
ratings of these three plans.  Because
whatever we have understood, it
is very important to understand it in combination that there is a company whose
product benefits are very good.  There
is a company whose customization is very good.  There
is a company whose claim performance
is very good.  How do we look at the combination
?  So ILM Research is a company which
basically rates insurance plans,
insurance companies on multiple parameters
and it does it in a completely unbiased manner.
Now I am saying unbiased, then why would you
believe it?  A simple way
to explain it is that this platform or this
research platform does not take any
commissions, marketing money, any affiliate
revenue, any advertising revenue from
any insurance company which insurers that they remain completely
unbiased.
So this rating is the rating of ILM Research.
We are going to tell you.
These ratings are based on three important parameters
and then there is an overall rating.
Quickly I will tell you.
ICICI Elevate gets 4.37 out of 5 in product benefits.
Aditya Birla Active One gets 5 out of
5.  So it's the best plan among all the
pluses that have been retold by my
research.  If someone is getting five then
that is the best plan.  Because the
rest of the people are rated according to five.  अह
4.59 इन केस ऑफ़ केयर हेल्थ अल्टीमेट केयर।
Meaning it is above 4.5.  All these plans are
good plans above average plans but Aditya
Birla Activ Max takes the cake.  They have the
highest rating in terms of the plan
quality and the product benefits that it
offers.  Now moving on to how customer service
rates in what we discussed.
4.24 In Case of ICI.  3.93 in case
of Aditya Birla and 4.49 in case of Air
Health.  So it means that care health is
performing the best in service.  Next is ICICI and
Aditya Birla is not performing as good,
is less than four which is not a good
rating.  You may face service issues
in Aditya Birla. The research that has been carried
out by ILM Research claims
experience varies greatly. Let us
understand the rating 3.84 for ICICI Bank,
4.98 in case of Aditya Birla, 4.98 near
perfect number, 4.61 in case of Care Health.
So basically the numbers of these three are
quite different numbers.  But Aditya Birla
is probably the highest in
the pack of three.  There is also 4.61 Care Health.
So it is a good number.  If you compare that.  Basically, the
experience number of ICICI regarding claims is not good.  So that's
a red flag for ICICI overall rating.
4.10 in case of ICIC 4.29 in
case of Aditya Birla and 3.74 in case of
Care Health.  So in comparison basically
Aditya Birla Act Max gets the highest
rating as per ILM Research.  It is very important
to understand that this gives
you a signal that this
plan is good compared to all other plans
on a standard metric and a standard
person.  But you are your own person.
You have your own needs.  You have your own
preferences.  You have your own history,
profile, medical history.  Considering all these
things, you should not decide which
plan you should take only on the basis of this.
You should basically list your preferences and
needs.  According to that, you should
match how the right plan is for you
?  Which one is better?  For
example, if you wanted maternity benefits.
Right?  So in what I told you, I did
not tell you whether there is maternity benefit or not.  Right?  But
if you need maternity benefits then it becomes very important that someone helps you understand which are the
best maternity benefits.  There are similar
OPD benefits.  There are many other similar
benefits.  If you have any
hospital specific needs, you have to
cover them.  For all these things,
you should sit and
decide with a good expert.  If there is such an expert in your area, your
location, or your circle, then
you can talk to him and understand the situation and
then you can take a plan.  It is
very important to find an expert who can
tell you this in someone's words.  You should check that
they have experience.  He has settled the claims.
He has a track record of
settling claims in the market.  Deal with such people.
If you are not able to find such experts.  Ca
n't find you in your circle.  Ca
n't find you among your friends.
So you can come, of course.  We have personally
curated one of the best insurance
experts and brought them to our platform.
These are not people who are typical call
center people who will learn the script for 2 months, memorize it and
explain it to you and force any
plan on you.  These are people who have actually seen
claims of minimum three
years to 20 years.  The average experience is 9
to 10 years.  This is CS, this is CFPs.
They have done some qualification or
course or are second generation insurance
experts who will sit and explain the plan to you.  We will
purchase it in the right manner and
after that we will stand by you in claims and will be
accountable to you.  Even if we have to
fight with the insurance company, we will fight.
If you want to consult such experts for
free, 100% free, then the
link is given in the description below, the
link is pinned in the comment.  You can book a consultation using it.
Our chat team will talk to you and
book a consultation for you.
And yes, if you have any doubts
about the things I mentioned,
or if you have any additional questions about something
I haven't mentioned in this comparison,
and you have questions about it, then you
can definitely ask us these questions in the comments, and we are more than happy to answer each of your questions, including
any
feedback you have about the videos that we do. And if you
find the video useful, please
press the like button below, we will be
very happy.